We live and die in the shadows,
for those we hold close
and for those we never meet.
The end you always
feared is coming.
The Anti-God.
This "entity" has
multiple personalities.
You're telling me this
thing has a mind of its own?
A self-aware, self-learning,
truth-eating digital parasite
infesting all of cyberspace.
An enemy that is everywhere
and nowhere and has no center.
Patiently listening,
reading, watching.
Harvesting our deepest
personal secrets for years.
Able to beguile, blackmail,
bribe or be anyone it wants.
Ethan, that is not me!
You're talking to the Entity.
Whoever controls the
Entity controls the truth.
...most secure data centers
are breached and corrupted.
The Entity will know precisely
how to undermine
our every strength.
Turn our allies into enemies...
And exploit our every weakness.
...and our enemies
into aggressors.
An unstoppable force of destructive power
that would just lay waste to everything.
The world is changing.
Truth is vanishing.
War is coming.
Good evening, Ethan.
This is your president.
Since you won't
reply to anyone else,
I thought I'd
reach out directly.
First, I want to thank you
for a lifetime of devoted
and unrelenting service.
Were it not for the tireless
dedication of you and your team,
the Earth would be a
very different place.
It might not even
be here at all.
Every risk you've taken...
every comrade you've
lost in the field...
every personal
sacrifice you made...
has brought this
world another sunrise.
It's been 35 years since
circumstances brought you to us
and you were given the choice,
since the IMF saved you
from a life in prison.
And though you never
followed orders,
you never let us down.
You were always
the best of men...
in the worst of times.
I need you to be that man now.
In the months since you
evaded capture in Austria,
every corner of cyberspace has
been infested by the truth-eating,
parasitic A.I. known
to us as the Entity.
Under its influence,
digital information has
been corrupted worldwide.
Nations and people no
longer know what to believe.
Antagonism,
aggression and martial law
are the new world order.
Exploiting this
paranoid atmosphere,
the Entity has inspired
a doomsday cult
with acolytes devoted to
ridding the world of corruption
through human extinction.
And He said unto
Noah, "Behold..."
"I will bring a
flood upon the earth
to destroy all flesh."
The children of the atom
shall rise from the ashes.
And the Entity will
help them rebuild.
These fanatics are secretly infiltrating
every level of law enforcement,
government and our military,
devoted to serving their
digital master's ultimate goal.
Our only hope of
controlling the Entity
relies on finding its
original source code.
If anyone knows the whereabouts
of this code, it's this man.
His identity, his past, his
very existence have been erased,
suggesting he is or was
in league with the Entity.
Austrian authorities have
his accomplice in custody.
But she has refused
to tell us anything.
Which brings us back to you.
You are in possession of a key
believed to be a vital component
in our struggle to acquire
the Entity's source code.
Yet you refuse to come in,
fearing any government will
weaponize this malicious A.I.
against the rest of the world.
Instead you've resolved
to kill the Entity,
a reckless act that would trigger
the total annihilation of cyberspace.
This would eradicate
the global economy,
plunging the world into
war and famine without end.
Agent Hunt. Ethan.
Please surrender.
Or the blood of the world
will be on your hands.
This message will
self-destruct in five seconds.
Come home, Ethan,
and bring us that key.
End it now! End it now!
End it now! End it
now! End it now!
Hey, Ethan.
Hey, Luther.
Sorry about the decor.
The Ritz was booked solid.
Well, some drapes, a few
throw pillows, and...
Yeah, a minibar.
Foosball table.
Hey, bro. Hey.
It's always good to see you on
the right side of the grass.
I'm worried you're
working too hard.
Don't worry about ol' Luther.
Okay.
So, what did you
manage to find out?
A lot.
More than I bargained for.
So, what's the play?
First,
we have to find Gabriel.
How do we find him?
You will betray us
because he spared your life.
STOP. STOP.
Wait, wait, wait!
Why...
did you spare my life?
Wait, wait, wait!
You call that in, it's the end
of the world... simple as that.
Degas, isn't it?
Clock is running.
You take us in, there won't be
anyone on Earth who can stop it.
There's a part of
you that knows that.
I can see it.
For God's sake, just
trust him! Wait, wait, no!
It's okay, it's okay!
Degas, it's okay. There's
no nations on this one.
There's no rival
ideologies, no dogma.
It's who keeps their
head and who panics.
The Entity wants you scared,
it wants us all scared.
It wants us divided.
It wants you to turn us in.
Don't do it.
He's gonna be okay.
Please, Degas.
Please.
We're friends.
Gabriel...
Where is he?
You shouldn't be in
there without backup.
Benji, please. We got this.
This is a terrible
idea. Just relax.
Ethan, this place is crawling
with clandestine services.
You should get out of there.
I see them. It's okay.
Stay calm, Benji.
I don't think Gabriel would
risk coming to that party.
Abort.
No, let's just hold
our nerve. He's here.
He's got to be here.
Ethan, for God's sake,
abort! We'll figure this out.
Not a problem yet.
Stay where you are.
Don't move, Hunt.
Are you sure it's really me?
All units, we have Hunt.
I repeat, we have Hunt.
They can't hear you.
Grace.
I didn't even see
you get that one.
What separates a good
pickpocket from a great one?
Timing.
Gentlemen?
Nice and slow.
Nothing personal.
You know, I like
the longer hair.
I really appreciate your coming,
but you shouldn't be here.
I didn't have much choice.
Will you expect
me to betray him?
I expect you to save
him from himself
and the world from him.
Kittridge.
You just bought yourself
a world of trouble, Grace.
The whole world's
in trouble, Ethan.
You're the only one
I trust to save it.
So, what's the play?
Grace!
Grace.
Gabriel's got a
job for you, Hunt.
Ethan, wake up!
Okay, what do we do?
Tell me you have a plan.
They took my watch.
Your watch? Yeah,
and my cuff links.
Had lock picks in them. I see.
We'll find a way out,
okay? Now, listen.
Ah, it's too late.
It's coming.
Okay, Grace, look at me.
You're gonna get through this.
Get through what?
Just keep telling yourself...
it's only pain.
Stop! Don't touch him!
You can't hurt him.
Not that way.
Take you back to Shanghai?
What was her name?
Julia!
The former Mrs. Hunt.
Did Ethan fail to mention her?
A fellow named
Davian took her...
and ransomed her for something
only Ethan could get.
Davian called it
the Rabbit's Foot.
But it had another name.
The Anti-God.
They never told you what was
in that canister, did they?
But you always wondered.
Stealing the Rabbit's
Foot was just one event
in a lifelong pattern,
repeating itself over and over.
For every life he's tried to
save, he's gambled millions more,
doubling down and down again.
And now the fate of every
living soul on Earth is
his responsibility.
You must be exhausted.
Where's the key?
Let her go.
Then we'll discuss it.
We don't have the time.
Someone you hold
close will die tonight
for the sake of those
you will never meet,
unless you do exactly as I say.
He also said the key would be
his on the train, remember?
You had one job:
Get on the train, get the
key, get off the train.
How did your master take the news
when it found out you blew it?
You failed,
and now the Entity
has forsaken you.
Your team's been
compromised, Ethan.
I know what Luther's doing.
I know what you're planning.
Resist me and I'll
make you pay dearly.
If you cooperate,
I can help.
In exchange for what?
You're searching for a Russian
submarine vanished on its maiden voyage.
The K559 Sevastopol.
A state-of-the-art submarine completely
undetectable to any known sonar.
And the secret to its
invisibility was that.
The Podkova.
A counter-acoustic
algorithmic drive
located in theSevastopol's
sonar sphere.
Now, in the winter of 2012
the Russians discovered a
computer virus of unknown origin
spreading through
their Black Sea fleet.
A digital covert operative.
We suspect this mystery
virus was only intended
to sabotage the Podkova, rendering
the submarine detectable.
Instead... It tricked the crew
into sinking themselves.
Captain! Our own torpedo
is not responding.
It's coming right at us!
Our torpedo's homing!
Range 400 meters!
Sound the collision alar...
If we're right, the one thing
we need to kill the Entity,
its original source code,
is buried in theSevastopol's
sonar sphere.
Somewhere deep at the bottom
of the ocean, frozen in time,
where even the Entity
can't reach it.
Now, the Podkova's housing was designed
to self-destruct if tampered with.
The only way to
safely open it...
is with a specially
designed cruciform key.
The two halves of which were held
by the Sevastopol's captain and XO.
They were pulled from
the drifting pack ice
in the spring of 2012
by Inuit fishermen.
A man of your skills
now has all he needs to pinpoint
that sub down to the square yard.
You think I'm gonna get the
source code and bring it to you.
I don't think. I know.
I'm gonna let you go.
Then you're gonna find the Entity's
source code and bring it to me
in exchange for Grace.
Then I'll take
control of the Entity,
the proverbial
genie you let out.
The Rabbit's Foot.
The Anti-God.
It wasn't a biological
or a chemical weapon
you took from Shanghai.
The vial you traded for Julia
contained malicious code.
The primordial digital ooze
from which a weapon evolved.
A weapon the East
couldn't make work.
A weapon the West might
never have made on their own.
You didn't know what
you were stealing.
None of us did.
I knew why I was stealing it.
They kidnapped my wife.
Stealing the Rabbit's Foot was
the only way I could get her back.
I sank that submarine as
much as the Entity did.
Without you, Ethan,
there'd be no Entity.
And if you don't find that
sub in the next few days...
It'